SAMUEL MWAMBURI MGHENDI

Nairobi, Kenya (+254) 716245353 | <u>sam.mwamburi@gmail.com</u> linkedin.com/in/mwamburi / github.com/mghendi

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A driven individual keen on developing clean and functional but complex systems. With close to three (3) years of experience in data and database management, data analysis and software development, I have a strong background in Math, Statistics and Programming.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF NAIROBI
M.Sc. Computational Intelligence

NAIROBI, KENYA SEPT. 2020 – DEC. 2022

MOI UNIVERSITY ELDORET, KENYA

B.Sc. Informatics SEPT. 2014 – DEC. 2019

Second Class Honors (Upper Division)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

UNITED NATIONS ENVIRONMENT PROGRAMME

Information Management Specialist

Nairobi, Kenya

JULY 2019 - PRESENT

- Design and implement data collection, analysis, and management frameworks for UNEP's projects-related data.
- Developed UNEP's programme delivery monitoring platform (PIMS+) to provide visibility of the organization's portfolio.
- Generate monthly status reports through the programme delivery monitoring platform for UNEP's Senior Management.

UNITED NATIONS ENVIRONMENT PROGRAMME

NAIROBI, KENYA

Information Management and Systems Intern

SEPT. 2017 - MAR. 2018

- Undertook the re-design and migration of UNEP's Online Document Repository (wedocs.unep.org).
- Conducted research on the potential applications of emerging technologies within UNEP.
- Prepared a proposal on how UNEP could leverage Big Data technologies and Machine Learning in its operations.

AMPATH KENYA ELDORET, KENYA

Information Technology Intern

MAY 2016 - AUG. 2016

- Accomplished timely administrative and technical support to AMPATH staff.
- Performed computer network, server and application maintenance, configuration and troubleshooting.
- Facilitated the expansion of the AMPATH's network coverage to its remote campus.

LANGUAGES

English (Native); Swahili (Bilingual)

AWARDS

- MEST Africa Scholarship, Meltwater Foundation, 2019
- Google Africa Challenge Scholarship, Google/Andela, 2018

REFERENCES

SAIFUL RIDWAN

Chief, Enterprise Solutions Unit, Corporate Services Division,

United Nations Environment Programme,

P. O. Box 30552 – 00100,

Nairobi, Kenya.

+254 709 023 649

saiful.ridwan@un.org

YASSIN AHMED

Sub-programme Coordinator, Environmental Governance, Policy and Programme Division,

United Nations Environment Programme,

P. O. Box 30552 – 00100,

Nairobi, Kenya.

+254 721 524 743

yassin.ahmed@un.org